《侏罗纪公园3》
(索拿岛 哥斯达黎加西方207英里)
(禁区)
都准备好了吧
Here you go, my friend.
你能开得越近越好
Make sure you get as close as you can!
干得好的话 另外有赏
I'll give you something extra if you make it a good trip!
我会尽量的 但不能太近
I'm gonna get you close, my friend, but not too close.
否则会被吃掉
You don't want to be eaten.
准备好了吗?
You ready, amigo?
好了
Ready!
一   二   三
One, two, three!
(恐龙飞伞)
艾瑞克  宾  加油
Eric! Ben!
怕吗?
Scared?
不怕  好刺激
Uh-uh, this is great!
有没有看到什么?
See anything yet?
还没有
No, not yet.
那是什么?
Whoa! What was that?
不知道
I don't know.
抓紧点  怎么回事?
Hold on. What's happening?
镇静点
Hold on!
叫他们停下来
Make it stop!
他们人呢?
What happened to them?
我不知道
I don't know.
我的天
Oh, my God!
- 我们要撞上了!  - 不会的
- We're gonna crash! We're gonna crash! -  No, we're not.
- 我先松绑 好放掉绳索  - 我们要撞上了!
- I'm gonna cut this loose! Let go of the rope!   - We're gonna crash!
手拿开
Move your hands.
快拿开  快一点
Come on!
放手
Here we go!
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay, bud.
那些是草食恐龙  所以不会互相攻击
Actually,those are herbivores.They wouldn't be interested in fighting each other.
这些是肉食恐龙  它们才喜欢互相蚕食
But these are carnivores, and they really like fighting with each other.
它们用牙和爪子  去撕裂对方的喉咙
They use their teeth and claws to rip each other's throats out.
阿伦  他才三岁  等五岁再教吧
Alan, he's three. Let's wait till he's five.
查理  抱歉啦
Oh, right. Sorry, Charlie.
- 艾丽  - 什么事?
- Ellie. -  What?
是汤姆  他要和你谈最后一章
It's Tom again. He has to talk to you about the last chapter.
告诉他我一定要引用杰克霍纳的话
Just tell him I'm not gonna lose the Jack Horner quote.
我的编辑认为他是古生物学家
My editor thinks he's a paleontologist.
马克  你看看是谁来了?
Hey, Mark. Hey, babe, look who's here.
这是阿伦
This is Alan.
很高兴见到你
Hi. Nice to meet you, Alan.
爸爸  这是草食恐龙  他是恐龙先生
Daddy,this's a herbivore and that's the dinosaur man.
恐龙先生
Dinosaur man?
杰克  我叫什么  是阿伦吗
Jack, say my name. Is my name Alan?
我名字是阿伦吗
Is my name Alan?
它本来知道的
He used to know me.
伤心吗
It's sad.
喝咖啡  谢谢
Here you go. Thanks.
马克现在在国务院做事
So you know Mark's working for the State Department now.
做哪方面的事?
Yeah. What do you do, Mark?
国际关系  多半是法律协定之类的事
International relations, mostly treaty law and things like that.
- 小家伙在抗议了   - 我去看看
- Call of the wild one. -  Here, I'll get her.
你们好好聊
You guys...catch up.
谢谢你
Thanks, babe.
他真是个好人
He's a great guy.
- 你都在研究什么?  - 以迅猛龙为主
- So, what are you working on now? -  Raptors, mostly.
我最喜欢的主题
My favorite.
你记得它们的声音吗
Do you remember the sounds they made?
我尽量不去想
I try not to.
过去我们对它们智慧和能力的
Ellie, all our theories about raptor intelligence,
评估相当不正确
what they're capable of we weren't even close.
- 快告诉我   - 我们做过头盖骨化石的扫描
- Tell me. -  We did cranium scans of a fossil skull.
发现了一个精密的共鸣腔
We found what looks like a very sophisticated resonating chamber.
等一下  所以当初我们说它们能发声是正确的
So we were right? They had the ability to vocalize?
我确信这是它们群居的关键
I'm convinced that's the key to their social intelligence.
也解释了它们的团队行动
Which explains why they could work together as a team.
能协调攻击  而不让被捕食者发现
And coordinate their attacks so the prey wouldn't know what was going on.
它们能互相交谈
They could talk to each other.
而且已超出我们的想象
To a degree we never imagined.
它们很聪明
Ellie, they were smart.
比海豚  鲸鱼更聪明
They were smarter than dolphins or whales.
甚至比灵长类还要聪明
They were smarter than primates.
我只想说如果你需要帮忙
I just want to say, if you ever need help with anything
别忘了找我
Sometimes you forget to ask.
尽管打电话来
So you can call me.
任何时间  任何事都行
Anything, anytime.
好的
Sure.
你仍是最杰出的
You're still the best.
这是真心话
I mean that.
可惜我是仅存的一个
The last of my breed.
经过多重的前腔研究
Through the painstaking study of the anterior chamber in multiple specimens,
我们确定了上颚和喉头的关联
we can determine the exciting correlation between the upper palate and the larynx.
依此推断  注意这是推断
This lets us theorize... theorize,
迅猛龙是可以发声的
mind you that the raptor was capable of sophisticated vocalizations...
由此可见这是一个巨大的进化
which would have been a tremendous evolutionary advantage.
迅猛龙它凶猛  聪明而且有社交能力
Raptors were fierce, intelligent and socially sophisticated.
他们知道分组出去猎食  并且能互相协调
They were able to hunt in numbers... and coordinate their efforts.
若不是洪水使它们绝迹
Were it not for the cataclysmic events which overtook them,
如今控制地球生物的
it's entirely possible that raptors rather than...
很可能不是人类  而是迅猛龙
humans would have become the dominant species on this planet.
希望这能引起你们的兴趣
I hope this has been of interest.
做为古生物学者  这个发现着实让人兴奋
It certainly excites us as paleontologists.
还有许多东西有待发掘
Sorry. There's much, much more to discover.
因此我们不断的请求你们的支持
That is why we continue to need and ask for your support.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
非常谢谢  格兰特博士
Thank you very much, Dr. Grant.
有问题吗
Now, does anyone have a question?
好
Fine.
谁有和侏罗纪公园无关的问题
Does anyone have a question that does not relate to Jurassic Park?
或是和我未参与的圣地亚哥事件无关的问题?
Or the incident in San Diego...which I did not witness?
您的问题
Yes, sir?
迅猛龙的理论很好  但都是猜测  是不是?
Your theory on raptors is good and all, but isn't all this conjecture moot?
一旦联合国和哥斯达黎加决定如何处置第二个岛屿后
Once the U.N. and Costa Rica and everyone decides how to handle that second island,
科学家一定会自行进入寻求线索
scientists will just go in and look for themselves.
恐龙生存在六千五百万年前
Dinosaurs lived 65 million years ago.
如今都已变成化石
What is left of them is fossilized in the rocks.
所以真正的发现是从岩石中得来的
And it is in the rock that real scientists make real discoveries.
汉蒙和遗传国际公司所做的
Now, what John Hammond and Ingen did
是在侏罗纪公园内  以基因制造出巨兽
at Jurassic Park...is create genetically engineered theme park monsters,
如此而已
nothing more and nothing less.
这么说即使有机会
Are you saying that you wouldn't want to get onto Isla Sorna...
你也不会到索拿岛去做研究
and study them, if you had the chance?
没有任何力量能让我去那个岛屿
No force on Earth or heaven could get me on that island.
奈许  都有什么武器
So, what we got here, Nashy?
20毫米铁角龙是半自动瓦斯操作
Iron horn 20-millimeter, gas-operated, semiautomatic,
十发旋转子弹
ten-shot magazine, rotating bolt,
减低后座力的枪支  烈性炸药  燃烧弹...
recoil-reducing muzzle break, high explosive incendiary...
我是余戴斯
Udesky.
我是保罗  刚检查...
Mr. Udesky, this is Paul Kirby. Just checking...
是的  我们这里已经准备就绪
Oh, yes, sir. We're good to go here.
等钱一付  一切就搞定
As a matter of fact,I can lock things down just as soon as you drop me that payment.
不错  这两个是最好的人选
Well, that's right. Two of the very best men I could possibly find.
你和他们一起工作过吗?
Have you worked with these men?
虽然没有一起工作过
No, sir, I haven't worked with them personally.
但介绍人极力推荐他们
But, believe me, sir, both of these men come very highly recommended.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事  你放心
Nothing to worry about, sir.
一定能轻松的达成任务
It's gonna be a walk in the park.
(蒙大拿州 峰垒湖)
比利  我的方法可能不对
Billy, I don't think I'm doing this right.
用牙刷试试看
Let's try the toothbrush.
一定要慢慢来
You got to go slowly.
一次一点
Just take a little bit at a time.
我老分不清岩石和骨头
I can never tell what's rock and what's bone.
其实都是岩石
Technically, it's all rock.
只不过骨头里的钙被石化而已
The calcium in the bones is replaced during fossilization.
你可以感到它们的不同  你瞧
But you can feel the difference. See?
粗糙  光滑
Rough... smooth.
Rough, smooth.
(洛矶山博物馆古生物学部门)
格兰特博士
Dr. Grant.
比利
Mr. Brennan.
有收获吗
So, how'd it go?
你还来得及改变主修科目
Well, it's not too late to change your major, Billy.
看来不太好
Not good, huh?
很糟  我们只剩四个礼拜的经费
Worse. We're gonna have to pack up in four weeks.
三个礼拜
Three.
我租了一些设备
I had to rent equipment.
给你看点东西
Come here, I gotta show you something.
你喜欢电脑  对不对
You like computers, right?
我还喜欢算盘呢
I like the abacus, Billy.
这就是古生物学的未来
Meet the future of paleontology.
这是快速原型机
It's a rapid prototyper.
我把迅猛龙头骨资料输入进去
I enter in the scan data from the raptor's skull.
电脑把它分成上千的切片
The computer breaks it down into thousands of slices.
然后这个设备就开始造型  一次一层
Then this thing sculpts it, one layer at a time.
(原型完成)
好了
It's done.
这就是迅猛龙的共鸣腔
I give you the resonating chamber of a Velociraptor.
你听
Listen to this.
太高明了
Wow. This is brilliant, Billy. Really, it is.
只可惜晚了点
Sad to say, it's just a little bit late.
格兰特博士吗
Dr. Grant?
我是克比企业公司的保罗
Paul Kirby. Kirby Enterprises.
这是我的名片  比利  你好
Uh, my card. How you doing, Billy?
有什么能为你效劳
What can I do for you, Mr. Kirby?
首先  我非常崇拜你
Well, um, first thing, I 'm a great admirer of yours,
其次  有个建议想和你讨论
and I have a proposition I'd like to discuss with you.
请你赏光今晚和我们共进晚餐
Would you have dinner with my wife and me this evening?
由我请客
It'll be our treat.
谢谢你的好意  我才旅行回来  很累
Well, that'd be great, but I'm tired. I've been traveling.
改天吧
Maybe some other time.
相信我  这很值得
Believe me, this will be worth your while.
- 就这么说定  - 太好了
- We'd love to. -  Oh, terrific.
- 我最欣赏这种精神  - 那就今晚见
- That's the spirit. Good. -  This evening then.
- 格兰特博士  比利  - 你好
- Oh, Billy. Dr. Grant. -  How are you?
- 阿曼达  比利  - 克比太太  你好
- Amanda, Billy. -  Mrs. Kirby, how are you?
你们要喝什么?
So what are you boys drinking?
- 冰钻鸡尾酒  - 来两杯
- Ice Pick, Catfish. -  Two, please, Cat.
我们很崇拜你的工作
We've admired your work for years.
非常具有启发性
Really truly inspiring.
阿曼达和我很喜爱户外生活
Amanda and I just love the outdoors.
几乎参加过所有的探险团
Heck, we've been on just about every adventure tour they can come up with.
象尼罗河  加拉帕哥斯群岛  喀喇昆仑山脉...
The Nile, Galapagos, K2.
我们甚至预订月球首航之旅
We even have two seats reserved on the first commercial flight to the moon.
所以在我们结婚纪念那天
And for our wedding anniversary this year...
想做点特别的活动
we wanted to do something really special.
- 那种  - 一生难忘的事
- Something So... -  Once in a lifetime.
所以我们包了一架飞机  到索拿岛去探险
I've chartered an airplane to fly us over Isla Sorna...
希望你做我们的向导
and we'd like you to be our guide.
酒来了
There you go, guys.
谢谢你的赏识  可是我很忙
That's a very kind offer, Mr. Kirby, but I'm a very, very busy man.
不过倒可以介绍几个  非常合格的人给你
I can recommend a couple of guys who are really highly qualified that
不  你曾亲眼看过它们  所以最合适
No, no, no. You're the best. You've seen these animals in the flesh.
你甚至曾和它们面对面过
There's no one that even comes close to you.
但依规定不能低飞  所以你根本看不到什么
You wouldn't be able to fly low enough to see anything of any real interest.
妙在他们特许我们低飞
Well, see? That's the interesting part...because we have permission to fly low.
多低?
How low?
我不是飞航专家  但我知道比任何人都低
I'm no aviation expert, but a heck of a lot lower than anybody else, I can tell you.
就我所知  要多低都行
From what I understand, it's pretty much. It's whatever we want.
真难以相信
That's hard to believe.
因为我的公司  所经营的进出口业务
You see, through my business dealings...import, export, emerging markets
使我结交了不少高层朋友
I've made a lot of friends in high places.
连哥斯达黎加的政府也不例外
In this case, the Costa Rican government.
你的参与对我们非常重要
Dr. Grant, you have no idea how important it is to us that you come along.
因为这是成功的关键
It would make all the difference.
克比太太
Mrs. Kirby, I-I...
我们也愿意捐款支持你的研究
And, of course, we'd love to make a contribution to your research here. So
任何数目都行
I could write all kinds of numbers on this check, Dr. Grant.
告诉我
Tell me
要多少钱?
what's it gonna take?
我付你的钱不少  买个好点的袋子吧
Even with what I pay you, couldn't you afford a better bag?
这是我的幸运袋
No way. This one's lucky.
几年前和朋友
A couple years ago, some buddies and I
到新西兰的峭壁上做滑翔飞行
went hang gliding off these cliffs in New Zealand
上升气流突然把我扫到一边
and this big updraft came and swept me right against the side, wham!
那的确很幸运
Wow, that does sound lucky.
就是这条背带救了我
This strap alone saved my life.
当我跌落时它刚好钩在岩石上
Got hooked on a rock as I was falling.
跟达尔文进化论刚好相反  "愚者生存"
Reverse Darwinism: survival of the most idiotic.
谢谢你给我这次机会
Alan, I want to thank you for bringing me along.
反正回来后骨头仍然在
Yeah, well, the bones will still be there when we get back.
研究骨头的好处就是它跑不了
That's the great thing about bones: They never run away.
当初是你把我扯进来
The truth is, you got me into this,
所以我绝不会放过你
and I have no intention of being on my own with these people.
别太兴奋
Don't get too excited, Billy.
很可能什么也看不到
Chances are we won't see a thing.
好啦  到时候拜托叫醒我
Your turn to be nice. Wake me when we get there.
你怎么认识克比的?
So, how do you know the Kirbys?
在教堂认识的
Uh, through our church.
阿伦
Alan.
醒醒  我们快到了
Wake up. We're almost there.
这里是圣胡安  一架不明飞机正接近索拿岛
Unidentified aircraft approaching Isla Sorna, this is San Juan Approach.
你在禁区飞行
You're flying in restricted airspace.
请尽快回头...
Immediately turn to coordinates two...
天呀  我几乎都忘了
My God, I'd forgotten.
亲爱的  我们终于到了
We did it, honey. We're here.
古伯  如果看到什么就大叫
Cooper, if you see anything, yell up.
不是说不准叫吗?
No, I thought I'd keep it to myself.
各位  从左边看过去
I'm sorry. Everyone, if you look out the left of the plane,
你们会看到成群的腕龙
you can see a whole herd of brachiosaurs.
雄性首领走在队伍的最前面
In fact, you can see in the front of the group, the alpha male grazing there.
余戴斯  奈许  前面有东西吗
Udesky, Nash, how 'bout up front? You guys see anything?
什么也没有
Nothing yet, Mr. Kirby.
从这边看过去是一群三角龙
You mean... Mrs. Kirby, look. Out here you'll see a group of triceratops
这里有跑道  要降落吗?
Mr. Kirby, we have a landing strip up ahead. You want me to put it down?
不要  先绕全岛一圈
No, no. I told you, I want to circle first, see the whole island.
你是什么意思  不能在这里降落
What do you mean set it down? You can't land here.
- 你说什么  - 等一下  我可以解释
- What are you talking about? -  Hold on. I can explain.
你绝不能在这岛上降落
You cannot land on this island.
没事的  你不明白
It's gonna be fine. You just don't understand.
- 你疯啦  - 拜托坐下来
- Are you crazy? -  Sit down, please.
格兰特博士  请你先坐下来
Dr. Grant, will you please sit down?
比利  我们没降落吧
Billy, tell me we didn't land.
艾瑞克  宾
Eric? Eric? Ben? Eric?
他们似乎在找人
I think they're looking for someone.
你没事吧  抱歉我们打...
Oh, Dr. Grant, are you all right? I'm sorry we had to be so...
谁打我的
Who hit me? Who hit me?
是古伯
That would be Cooper.
他们在做什么
What are they doing?
清理四周  使这里更安全
They're setting up a perimeter to make the place safe.
相信我 这里没有安全的地方
These guys are good. On this island, there is no such thing as safe.
我们最好回到飞机上
We have to get back on that plane.
让你太太别叫了  这样太危险
Will you tell your wife to stop making that noise? That is a very, very bad idea.
阿曼达
Amanda!
阿曼达宝贝  格兰特博士说  那样很危险
Ben? Amanda? Honey? Dr. Grant said that's a bad idea.
什么
What?
他说太危险
He says it's a bad idea!
什么危险
What's a bad idea?
那是什么
What was that?
是霸王龙
That's a tyrannosaurus.
不是  比霸王龙还要大
I don't think so. It sounds bigger.
我们得马上离开
We have to leave! We have to leave now!
怎么回事
What's going on?
到飞机上去
Get in the plane!
另外那个人呢
What about the other guy?
古伯能保护自己的
Cooper's a professional. He can handle himself.
快上去
Get in the plane! Hurry!
别怕
It's all right.
保罗  我们不能
Paul, we can't...
没关系  我们只绕着岛飞
It's all right. We'll just circle the island.
帮我一下
Give me a hand, Udesky.
停下来
Hey! Stop!
- 他想干什么  - 那是古伯
- What are you doing? -  That's Cooper.
求求你停下来
Please stop.
走开
Coop, get out of the way.
你知道我不能停
You know I can't stop this plane.
天呀
Oh, my God!
燃料被切断  我们要坠毁了
Fuel cut off!  We're going down!
你没事吧?
You okay?
我们也没事
We're okay up here.
大家别乱动
Everyone just stay put.
呼叫圣胡安  请求援助
San Juan Approach, Mayday!
谁有卫星电话
Who has the satellite phone?
我有
I do.
就在这里
I got it right here.
无线电通话器坏了
I'm not getting anything. The radio's gone.
我们还没着陆呢
We haven't landed yet.
所有线路都在忙线中  该死
All circuits are busy. Damn it! Oh, man.
那是什么
What was that?
不要动
Keep still! Keep still! What?
那是什么
What is it? What?
到底是什么  抓稳了
What is it? Hold it!
大家抓紧
Hang on, everyone!
救命呀
No! No! Help me!
克比太太  快回来
Mrs. Kirby, come back!
阿曼达
Amanda!
跟着我  往这边走
Follow me! This way!
到这里来
In here!
应该甩掉它了
I think we lost him.
没关系  是死的
It's okay, it's dead.
大家都不准动
Nobody move a muscle.
请你别打了
No, no, no. Please, please don't. Stop, p-please.
你最好给我个解释
It's time you did some explaining, Mr. Kirby.
我们求过所有的人
We called everyone.
试过所有办法  根本没用
We did everything we could. No one would help us.
哥斯达黎加政府说这里是禁止飞行区
The Costa Rican government said this is a no-fly zone.
美国大使馆...
The U.S. Embassy...
我们自己的大使馆
that's our U.S. Embassy told us...
居然叫我们接受事实
we should accept the inevitable. Can you believe that?
你怎能让12岁小孩单独飞拖曳伞
You let a 12-year-old go parasailing alone?
不是
No!
他和我朋友一起
He wasn't alone. He was with a friend of mine.
他的名字是宾
Ben Hildebrand.
我和保罗一年前离婚了
Paul and I divorced over a year ago.
为什么找我?
So why me?
他说需要找曾到过岛上的人
He said we needed someone who'd been on the island before.
可是我没叫你去绑架呀
Yes, but I did not tell you to kidnap somebody.
我没来过这座岛
I have never been on this island.
你书都写了 怎么会没有
Sure you have. You wrote that book.
那是努布拉岛  这是索拿岛  B地
That was Isla Nublar. This is Isla Sorna, site "B."
有两个不同的恐龙岛?
You mean there are two islands with dinosaurs?
好了  没你的事
You stay out of this!
他们失踪多久了
So how long have they been missing?
八个星期
Eight weeks.
将近八个星期
Almost eight weeks now.
比利 我们到飞机里尽量多拿点东西
Billy. We go back to the plane and salvage what we can,
然后就朝海边走
then we make for the coast.
格兰特博士  找不到儿子我们绝不离开
Dr. Grant, we're not leaving this island without our son.
你可以自己去找
Then you can go and look for him...
否则就跟着我们 不准生事
or you can stick with us as long as you don't hold us up.
到头来...  恐怕还是死路一条
Either way... you probably won't get off this island alive.
我们现在怎么办
So... what do we do?
仍旧去寻找你儿子  但和他们走同一个方向
We search for your son...in the direction that they're going.
好主意
Excellent. Excellent.
对不起
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
又不是没看过
It's nothing you haven't seen before, Paul.
你瘦了多少
How much weight did you say you lost?
大约25磅  因为我常游泳
About 25 pounds. I've been swimming.
你讨厌游泳  而且根本不会游
Swimming? You hate to swim. You don't even know how to swim.
我是特别去学的
I know. I learned.
- 你看起来很棒  - 你也是
- You look good. -  So do you.
该怎么归类?
How would you classify it, Billy?
应该是超级肉食性恐龙
Well, it's a superpredator.
鼻子长长的
Suchimimus. Snout.
还要再大些
No, think bigger.
难道是重爪龙
Baryonyx?
重爪龙没有鳍
Not with that sail.
是棘背龙
Spinosaurus Aegypticus.
但它并不在遗传国际公司的目录内
I don't remember that on Ingen's list.
既然不在目录内
Because it wasn't on their list,
那他们可能还搞了其它名堂
and that makes me wonder what else they were up to.
克比  告诉我  当你攀登昆仑山时
So, Mr. Kirby. Tell me when you climbed K2,
基地是设在两万五还是三万尺
did you base camp at 25 or 30,000 feet?
三万尺  非常接近山顶
Thirty thousand feet. We were close to the top.
那比实际山高还超出一千尺
You were about a thousand feet above it, actually.
这是很常见的错误
No, no, that's a common mistake. Mr. Kirby.
根本就没有克比企业  是不是
There's no such thing as Kirby Enterprises, is there?
是克比油漆地砖及其它
It's Kirby Paint and Tile Plus.
所谓其它是指浴室设备
The plus stands for bathroom fixtures.
我们是在俄克拉荷马州的西门购物中心内
We're in the Westgate Shopping Center, Enid, Oklahoma.
看来那张支票也不能兑现
So I don't suppose that check you wrote us is any good.
我一定会付你的  没问题的
This is good. This is good. I will pay you, no matter what.
我们身处绝境  居然还被耍
Here we are in the worse place in the world, and we're not even being paid.
你们别生气  这样好了
Now, wait, fellas. Hold on. I'll make this up to you.
将来你想装修浴室或厨房...
If you ever do a bathroom or a kitchen...
你也不是什么雇佣兵
You're not really a mercenary, are you?
我从没这么说过
I never said I was.
那也对
That's true.
那你是干什么的
What are you?
我是中介人
Well, I'm like a booking agent.
有个人生病不能来
One of the guys got sick and couldn't come.
借过 让我来
Excuse me. Here.
你开五金店
So you run a hardware store?
是油漆和地砖
Paint and tile. Yeah. Hmm.
人不可貌相
You never can tell about people, can you?
我同意
Ain't that the truth?
- 艾瑞克  - 不要叫
- Eric? -  Quiet.
你别叫  格兰特博士说这里很危险
Would you stop that? Dr. Grant says this is very dangerous territory.
我们应该分两路 才能找更多的地方
Maybe we should split up or something. We could cover twice as much ground.
格兰特博士说那样不好
Dr. Grant says that's a bad idea.
又是格兰特博士说...
"Dr. Grant says..."
既然雇了专家  为什么不听他的话
What's the good of hiring an expert if we're not gonna use his advice?
可惜他不找艾瑞克  而是找海边
Yeah, except Dr. Grant isn't looking for Eric. He's looking for the coast.
那你就去喊
Okay, fine. Go ahead and scream.
等那支三什么龙攻击你时 别哭着来找我
Then when that tricycloplots attacks you, don't come crying to me.
- 不用你费心  - 什么
- Don't worry about that. -  What?
- 没什么  - 你说什么
- Nothing. Never mind. -  What did you say?
天呀  别啰唆了
What did you say? God, Paul, just drop it.
如果分开走  我要和你们一组
If we split up, I'm going with you guys.
艾瑞克
Eric!
克比先生和克比太太
Mr. and Mrs. Kirby.
他们还在附近的可能性很低
Mrs. Kirby, the chances are remote they're still in the vicinity.
是艾瑞克的
Young adult.
你们看
Hey, guys.
那是我的摄影机  等等
That's my camera. Wait.
电池没了
The battery's dead.
我有个主意
I got an idea.
摄影机给我
Let me have the camera.
妈  你在哪里?
Where were you on that one, Ma?
好  俯冲  俯冲
Okay, dive, dive. Okay, diving.
老妈  你应该接住
Come on, Ma! You were supposed to catch it.
这是他失踪那天拍的
I shot this the morning they disappeared.
给我  让我拿  给我嘛
No, I want that. Let me take that. Come on, give me that.
有没有看到什么?
See anything yet?
还没有
No, not yet.
那是什么
What was that?
把夹子打开 还有个大钩子 我看不到
Unclip us. There's a big clip. I can't see.
我没办法
I can't do it.
我先把你松开
I'm gonna unhook you, all right?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
好  我现在下来
Okay, buddy? I'm gonna drop myself down now.
摄影机还在拍
The camera's still on.
我就知道他还活着
He's alive. I know he's alive.
我们得去找他
We're gonna find him.
你能飞那家伙吗
Can you fly one of those?
只要伞没坏 应该可以
Maybe, as long as the sail's not torn.
那把它拿下来
Well, let's take it.
如果有飞机经过 这该能引起驾驶员的注意
If we spot a plane, it might be a good way to get attention.
向这边拉
Pull it over this way.
我拿开了
I'll get it. I'll get it.
你没事了
Okay, okay.
好啦  全拿掉了
Okay, okay, you're free.
克比  把她追回来
Get her back, Mr. Kirby.
阿曼达  等等
Amanda! Wait!
阿曼达
Amanda?
阿曼达 你停下来
Amanda, stop, stop, stop.
宾的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry about Ben.
这和宾无关
It's not Ben, Paul.
是艾瑞克
It's Eric.
他一个人孤军奋斗
He's out there all by himself.
我知道
I know, I know.
我们的孩子一个人在这里
Our baby's out here all by himself.
我向你保证我们一定会找到他
Listen to me. We'll find him. I promise.
保罗
Paul.
格兰特博士
Dr. Grant!
你快来看
You should come look at this!
迅猛龙
Raptor!
你听着  我们一定会找到他
We're gonna find him. You listening to me? We're gonna find him.
这孩子有小聪明
The kid's got resources.
记得以前我们罚他禁足  他却花招百出吗?
Remember what it was like to try to ground him?
比利呢
Where's Billy?
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
我在拍鸟巢
I was photographing the nest.
别再那么做
Don't do that again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
如果失去你  叫我怎么和那些人相处
If we lose you, it's just me and the damn tourists.
艾瑞克一定在那里
I bet you Eric's in there.
我赌最后一块钱
Don't you think? I'd bet my bottom dollar.
你说呢?
What do you think it is?
对我来说它是五星级酒店
As far as I'm concerned, it's the Four Seasons.
艾瑞克
Eric!
别叫
Paul, don't!
赌个运气吧
What the hell?
谁能换零钱  它只收两毛五的铜板
Who's got some change? It only takes quarters.
我有一块十分钱
I got, like...I got a buck ten.
这就是你们制造恐龙的方式
This is how you make dinosaurs?
不  这是扮演上帝的方式
No. This is how you play God.
这边
This way! This way!
锁住了
It's locked!
来这边 快
This way! This way! Go! Go!
这边
Hey! Over here! Hey! Over here!
推
Push!
我的天
My God.
它在向同伴求救
He's calling for help.
快走
Come on! Come on!
(遗传国际公司)
朝草食龙群里跑
Head to the herd!
到树上去
Head for the trees!
余戴斯呢?
Udesky.
克比
Mr. Kirby?
比利
Billy?
阿伦和你在一起吗?
Is Alan with you?
天啊
Oh, my God.
余戴斯?
Mr. Udesky?
他死了
He's dead.
不  他没死
Oh, my God, no, he's not!
- 等一下  似乎不对劲  - 我们得去帮他
- No, wait! Something's not right. -  We gotta help him.
阿曼达
Amanda!
等一下
Hold on!
圈套  它们居然设下圈套
They set a trap. They actually set a trap.
你们在说什么?
What are you saying?
你们在找什么
What are you looking for?
等一等
Wait!
谢谢你
Thanks.
艾瑞克  真谢谢你
Thanks a lot, Eric.
你知道我是谁?
You know who I am?
是的  你父母也到这里找你
Yeah. Your parents are here. They're looking for you.
一起?
Together?
对  一起
Together.
不好  他们在一起就吵架
That's not good. They don't do so well together.
为了找你  他们相处得还不错
You'd be surprised what people can do when they have to.
你是阿伦·格兰特
You're Alan Grant.
你来这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
你父母... 邀我一起来
Your parents, uh, invited me along.
你的两本书我都看过
I read both of your books.
我喜欢第一本写你在岛上的书
I liked the first one more.
以前你蛮喜欢恐龙的
Before you were on the island. You liked dinosaurs back then.
以前它们并没有要吃我
Back then they hadn't tried to eat me yet.
他们搬走时留下不少东西
When Ingen cleared out, they left a lot of stuff behind.
有武器吗?
Any weapons?
没了 我用了最后一个瓦斯弹
No. And I just used the last of the gas grenades.
谢谢你救了我
And I appreciate that.
小心一点  那是霸王龙的
Be careful with that. T-rex.
会把小的恐龙吓跑  却会吸引更大的来
It scares the smaller ones, but attracts one really big one with a fin.
这是霸王龙的尿
This is T-rex pee?
你怎么弄来的
How'd you get it?
还是不知道的好
You don't wanna know.
要甜点吗?
Dessert?
好
Sure.
你能在岛上活八周  真的让我很惊讶
Eric, I have to tell you, I'm astonished that you've lasted eight weeks on this island.
才过了八个星期吗
Is that all it's been?
活着是最重要的
You're alive, and that's the important thing.
幸好有你  否则我必死无疑
And thanks to you, that's one thing that we have in common.
你看过马尔科姆博士的书吗
Did you read Malcolm's book?
看过
Yeah.
怎么样
So?
我觉得很唠叨
I-I don't know. I mean, it was kind of preachy.
而且乱成一团
And too much chaos. Everything's chaos.
他似乎自以为高人一等
It seemed like the guy was kind of high on himself.
我深有同感
That's two things that we have in common.
你听
Listen.
是秀颌龙
Compys!
阿伦
Alan!
不管怎样 这不是你的错
No matter how this turns out, it wasn't your fault.
艾瑞克是个意志坚强的孩子
Eric's always been a strong-willed kid.
一直都是这样
Always.
后来你把宾给扯进来
Then you throw someone like Ben Hilde brand into the mix
那是...
Well...
"那是"什么?
"Well" what?
我只想说这不是你的错
All I'm saying...It's not your fault.
不  如果他和你一起 就不会出事
No, if he'd been with you, he'd be completely safe.
你开车永远低于最高限速
You drive five miles under the speed limit, Paul.
而我三年中撞毁了三辆车
And I've totaled three cars in three years.
不是三辆  别克车并没有全毁
Well, not three. The Buick wasn't really totaled.
我那样说是因为  我想买新的多功能运动车
I just said it was 'cause I wanted to get the S.U.V.
对不起要你来这里受罪
I am so sorry that you have to be here.
我倒不觉得
I'm not.
在堤岸边有条船
Yeah, there's a boat right alongside the bank.
看起来还能开
Looks in good shape.
是援救船吗
Rescue boat?
不是
No, no.
以前留下来的船  至少它能浮起来
Just something left behind. But it floats.
我们依计行事
We stick to the plan.
朝海边出发
Head to the coast.
你不去找格兰特博士吗
You're not gonna look for Dr. Grant?
到海岸去是他的主意
Going to the coast was Alan's idea.
若他活着   一定会朝那边走
If he's alive, that's where he's headed.
我同意
I agree.
那艾瑞克呢?
What about Eric?
他很聪明  应该想到海边的机会比较大
Eric's a smart kid. He probably knows he stands his best chance by the coast.
而且大恐龙都集中在岛中间
He figures all the big dinosaurs are in the center of the island.
是不是
Right?
是的
Sure.
你知道这是什么
Know what this is?
迅猛龙的爪子  我以前也有一个
That's a raptor claw. Used to have one.
是化石的
A fossil.
我的是新鲜的
Mine is new.
岛上你已经探勘过多少地方?
How much of the island did you explore?
我一直留在这附近
I stayed pretty close to the compound.
我想如果有人找我  一定会来这儿
I figured if anyone came looking for me, that's where they'd start.
我们的计划是到海边
We need to get to the coast. That was the plan.
你确定  离水越近恐龙越大
Are you sure? Closer you get to the water, the bigger things get.
如果能下到峡谷
Well, if we can find our way down into the canyon,
就能沿着河到海边
we could follow the river out to the coast.
先去找你的父母
After we find your parents.
然后呢
And then what?
一步一步来
One step at a time.
你听
Listen.
听什么
What?
那是我老爸的卫星电话
That's my dad's satellite phone!
等一下  你怎么知道的
Wait a minute! How do you know?
西门中心的克比油漆和地砖
Kirby Paint and Tile Plus, in Westgate!
爸爸
Dad!
妈妈
Mom!
艾瑞克
Eric! Eric!
艾瑞克  走这边
Eric! This way! Eric! Eric!
妈妈  爸爸
Mom! Dad!
艾瑞克
Eric! Mom!
妈妈 爸爸
Mom! Dad! Mom! Dad!
我就知道能找到你
I knew it! My God! I knew it.
真高兴看到你
Am I glad to see you.
你拣到我的袋子
Hey, you got my bag.
有幸运的背带啊
Yeah. Lucky strap.
让我拿好了
Want me to carry it?
我们需要找个缺口
We need to find a gap here.
你怎么知道我们在这里?
How did you know we were here?
我听到电话铃响
The phone. That stupid jingle from the store, I heard it.
我的电话
My phone?
就是你的卫星电话在哪里
Yeah, your satellite phone. Where is it?
我没有呀
I don't have it.
你最后在哪里用它
When did you use it last?
飞机上
Uh, uh, on the plane.
- 在飞机上我接了一通电话...  - 后来呢
- I got a call on the plane, and... -  What?
怎么啦  我借给奈许
What! I loaned it to Nash.
难道说当他...
He must've had it when he...
快跑
Run.
把袋子给我吧
Alan, you wanna give me the bag back?
我拿着没关系
That's okay, Billy, I got it.
请你还给我
Please give me the bag.
它不安全
It's not safe.
迅猛龙的蛋
Raptor eggs.
你偷了迅猛龙的蛋
Did you steal raptor eggs?
我终于明白了
Now it all makes sense.
我发誓当初没想到 你会捡到我的袋子...
I swear... if I'd known that you were gonna end up with them...
我真的是一时冲动
I took 'em on an impulse.
只想到它价值高
I thought they'd be worth a fortune,
至少能换得十年的研究基金
enough to fund the dig site another ten more years.
请你相信我  我知道我这样做很愚蠢
Look, you have to believe me. This was a stupid decision.
但是全出自于一片好意
But I did it with the best intentions.
出自一片好意
With the best intentions.
许多最坏的情况  就是出自一片好意
Some of the worst things imaginable have been done...with the best intentions.
比利 依我看
Billy, as far as I'm concerned,
你和建这个岛的人一样糟
you're no better than the people that built this place.
你想干什么  那些家伙就是为了蛋才追我们
What are you doing? Those things are after us because of those.
"那些家伙"知道我们有蛋
"Those things" know we have the eggs.
就算丢到河里去  它们仍会追我们
I drop them in the river, they'll still be after us.
若抓到我们和蛋呢
What if they catch us with 'em?
若抓到我们没有蛋呢
What if they catch us without 'em?
在下游处有条船
There's a boat at the bottom, just downriver.
我们尽量逃到海边去
We can try and make it to the coast, at least.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
一次先过一个人
Let's do this one at a time, shall we?
好  过来
Okay, come on over!
一次一个人
One at a time!
好  艾瑞克  我离开你一下
All right, Eric, I'm gonna leave you just for a minute, okay?
你就在我后面
Then you're gonna be right behind me, okay?
妈  我一个人  待在给水车里八周
Mom, I've been alone in a water truck for eight weeks.
两分钟没有你  不会有问题
I think I can manage the next two minutes without you.
对  我们已经团圆了
All right. We're all together now.
好了  艾瑞克
Okay, Eric!
过来吧
Okay. Over you go.
你去吧
Come on, honey.
妈妈
Mom?
糟糕
Oh, my God.
怎么啦
What is it?
这是个鸟笼
It's a birdcage.
什么鸟的笼子
For what?
爸爸
Dad.
艾瑞克?
Eric!
艾瑞克
Eric. Eric!
救命呀
Help me!
我看不到他
I can't see him! I can't see him!
艾瑞克
Eric! Eric!
不要
No, no!
这边
This way!
比利
Billy? Billy?
停下来
Billy, stop. Billy, stop!
比利  不要
Don't, Billy!
比利
Billy!
艾瑞克  坚持下去
Eric, hold on!
艾瑞克
Eric!
跳过来
Jump!
比利
Billy!
你先下去
Let go now!
艾瑞克?  他在那里
Eric? He's there.
艾瑞克
Eric?
他在那儿  在河那边
There he is! He's across the river!
把他带走
Get him outta here!
- 我们走  - 比利怎么办?
- Go, Eric. No, no. -  What about Billy?
撑下去
Billy! Wait.
别去
Get away.
你们走开
Get away!
快走开
Paul!
我们有足够的汽油
There's plenty of gasoline.
只要能到海边就好了
Now we just gotta make our way to the coast.
我们可以发出信号
Work out some sort of a signal.
生火或什么的  好让他们能看到
Build a fire or something. Something they can see from the air.
格兰特博士
Dr. Grant?
你怎么样
Hey, Eric, how you doing?
失去比利你一定很难过
I'm sorry about Billy.
你知道 我对他说的最后一句话吗
You know what the last thing I said to him was?
我说
I said,
"你和建这个岛的人一样糟"
"You're as bad as the people that built this place."
那只是气话  他太年轻气盛
Which wasn't true. Billy was just young.
如此而已
That's all.
我认为男孩可分两类
I have a theory that there are two kinds of boys.
一类想成为天文学家
There are those that want to be astronomers,
一类想做太空人
and those that want to be astronauts.
天文学家和古生物学家一样
The astronomer, or the paleontologist,
在完全安全的地方做研究
gets to study these amazing things from a place of complete safety.
可惜永远不能上太空
But then you never get to go into space.
没错 差别就在想象和亲眼所见
Exactly. That's the difference between imagining and seeing:
并能亲手摸到它们
To be able to touch them.
那也是比利最渴望的
And that's... that's all that Billy wanted.
格兰特博士
Dr. Grant.
格兰特博士  你知道吗
Know something, Dr. Grant?
比利是对的
Billy was right.
你们听
Listen!
在挂断前快找到它
Find it before it stops ringing!
艾瑞克 你留在船上
Eric, you stay on that boat.
在这里 不对 是这里
It's here. Wait. Whoa-whoa, it's here.
找到了
I got it.
喂?
Hello? Hello!
你可拥有位于瓜达拉哈市的
You too can own a time-share...
渡假别墅的共同所有权
in beautiful Guadalajara.
并在我们的四星级餐厅用餐
Enjoy a meal in one of our four-star restaurants
小心
Look out!
剩下来的电池  只够我们打一通电话
Turn off the power. You've got juice for maybe one call.
千万别打给美国大使馆  他们什么事也不做
Whatever you do, don't call the U.S. Embassy. They won't do a damn thing.
你们过来看呀
Hey, guys! Come here! Look at this!
鲣鱼
Bonitos.
它们被吓坏了
Something must have spooked them.
克比  别让引擎停下来
Get the engine going, Mr. Kirby.
把节流阀打开
Open the throttle.
接电话
Pick up, pick up.
喂?
Hello?
艾丽吗?
Ellie?
喂?
Hello?
查理
Charlie!
查理 把电话拿给妈咪
Charlie! Take the phone to Mommy now.
快把电话拿给妈咪
Charlie, take the phone to Mommy now.
是恐龙先生打来的
It's the dinosaur man.
好
Okay.
听我说
Listen to me, Charlie.
查理  有没有把电话给妈咪?
Charlie, are you taking the phone to Mom?
查理?
Charlie!
哈 哈 哈  大家好
Oh, ho-ho. Hi, everybody!
这里真不错  你们好吗?
It's great to be here! Hi, there! How are you today?
一定会很棒的
This is gonna be great!
- 谁打来的?  - 恐龙先生
- Who's on the phone? -  The dinosaur man.
是吗  阿伦
He is? Alan?
找找看盒子里有没有武器
Look in the boxes! Find a weapon!
电话呢?  快去接
Where's the phone? There! Get the phone!
艾丽  听我说
Ellie? Ellie, listen to me.
你用手机吗  我听不到
Alan, are you on a cell phone? I can't hear you?
B地的河流
The river! Site "B"! The river!
喂?
Hello?
爸爸
Dad! Dad!
保罗
Paul!
爸爸
Dad!
保罗 你这个混蛋
Paul, you jerk!
你怎么能就这样走了
You can't leave me like this!
我没走呀
I'm not going anywhere.
还记得几年前的夏天  我们去钓鱼吗
Remember when we went fishing a couple summers ago?
当我把船卸下来时  拖车反而沉了
I was putting the boat in the water, and the trailer sank?
拖吊车想把车拉上来  自己反而越陷越深
The tow truck tried to pull us out, and it got dragged in too.
气得司机差点揍我一顿
The truck driver wanted to knock my lights out.
我真想念钓鱼
I miss fishing.
克比
Mr. Kirby?
你找的那位女士...  她是谁
That lady you called. Who is she?
她真能帮我们吗?
How do you know that she can help us?
她是我唯一能信任的人 我欠她太多了
She was the one person I could always count on. I owe her a lot.
可惜一直没对她说
Although I don't think I ever told her that.
你应该说
You should.
你听到了吗
Shh. You hear that?
是海洋
The ocean!
它们向我们要蛋
They want the eggs,
否则我们早死了
otherwise we'd be dead already.
大家蹲下来  它在向我们挑战
Everybody get down. She's challenging us.
它以为你偷了蛋
She thinks you stole the eggs.
到我后面去
Get behind me.
把蛋给我
Give me the eggs.
妈  快给它
Do it, Mom.
不对  要发求救信号
No! No, no, no. Call for help.
是直升机
That's a helicopter.
格兰特博士
Dr. Grant? Dr. Alan Grant?
不要叫
Stop!
那样太危险
That's a very bad idea!
你一定要好好谢她
Wow. You have to thank her now.
连海军和海军陆战队都出动了
She sent the navy and the marines!
艾丽  你真是救命恩人
God bless you, Ellie.
格兰特博士  这个人是和你一起来的吗
Dr. Grant, this man with you?
谁?
What?
你逃出来了
Hey, you made it.
是呀
Yeah.
我救了你的帽子
I rescued your hat.
格兰特博士  我们得起飞了
Dr. Grant, we need to go now.
喔  是呀
Oh, yeah.
这倒是挺重要的
Well, that's the important thing.
格兰特博士
Dr. Grant!
请你坐下来  系上安全带
Can I get you to sit here and buckle up, sir?
海影对尘暴  一共援救了五人
Sea Shadow Dust Storm Zero Five, six souls on board.
尘暴对海影  知道了  干得好
Dust Storm Sea Shadow, roger. Good work.
搞什么鬼呀
What the hell is that?
格兰特博士 你快看
Dr. Grant, look!
它们要飞到哪里去
Where do you think they' re going?
不知道  也许去找新地方筑巢
I don't know. Maybe just looking for new nesting grounds.
对他们来说外面是全新的世界
It's a whole new world for them.
别想到俄克拉荷马州来筑巢
I dare 'em to nest in Enid, Oklahoma.
咱们回家吧
Let's go home.